Finding Aid for the Otto Kinkeldey Papers, 1898-1962
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Transcriptions by Kinkeldey, circa 1900-1940, IX.; Folder 73-146
  - Attaingnant, Pierre, fl. 1528-1549 Selections from five publications by Pierre Attaingnant, undated, 26 pages of manuscript music; 36 cm.; Ink manuscript. Transcribed for keyboard format. (Box 3, Folder 75)
    Tabulature pour le jeu dorgues, espinettes et manichordions sur le plain chant de cunctipotens et Kyrie Fons. Avec leurs et in terra. Patrem. Sanctus et Agnus dei. [Paris, 1531]. (Königliche Hof u Staatsbibliothek München Mus. fr. 232). Kyrie; Christe; Kyrie [through Fol. BIII] -- Magnificat sur les huit tons avec Te Deum laudamus et deux Preludes, le tout mys en tabulature des Orgues Espinettes et Manicordions, et telz semblables instrumentz... 1530. Preludium Fol L1(v); Prelude sur le chacun ton Fol LIV(v); Magnificat primi toni Fol NI; Secundus versus Fol NIV -- Treze Motetz musicaulx avec ung Prelude, le tout reduict en la Tabulature des Orgues Espinettes et Manicordions et telz semblables instrumentz... Kal. Aprilis 1531. Fortuna desperata Fol 83 AaIII (v); Sicut malus Fol 89; Prelude Fol 119 (v) -- Dixneuf chansons musicales reduictes en la tabulature des Orgues Espinettes Manichordions, et telz semblables instrumentz musicaulx... Idibus Januraii 1530. Fors seulement Fol 18 (v) -- Vingt et cinq chansons musicales reduictes en la tabulature des Orgues Espinettes Manichordions, et telz semblables instrumentz musicaulx... Kal. 1530. [Contents listed but no musical examples transcribed] -- Vingt et six chansons musicales reduictes en la tabulature des Orgues Espinettes Manichordions, et telz semblables instrumentz musicaulx... Non. Februaii 1530. Ma bouche rit Fol 110 (v) -- Quatorze gaillardes neuf paven nes sept branles et deux basses dances le tout reduict de musique en la tabudu jeu dorgues espinettes manichordions a telz semblables instrumentz musicaulx ... [1531]. Pavane Fol 1 (v); Gaillarde sur la pavane -- Vingt et six chansons musicales reduictes en la tabulature des Orgues Espinettes Manichordions, et telz semblables instrumentz musicaulx... Non. Februaii 1530. Le content est riche Fol XCII (v) (includes text).
  - Auszug aus dem Katalog der Hamburger Stadtbibliothek: Lauten Tabulaturen Abschriften undated, 6 manuscript pages; Ink manuscript. Notes about holdings in the Staats- und Universita¨tsbibliothek Hamburg pertaining to lute tablature. No musical transcriptions are included. (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750 Brandenburgische Konzert. Nr. 2. Andante; arr. Brandenburg Concert II: Andante undated, 3 pages of manuscript music; 35 cm.; Manuscript in ink. Arranged for piano; incomplete. (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Bataille, Gabriel, 1575-1630 Airs de diffe´rents autheurs mis en tablature de luth. Selections Airs de diffe´rents autheurs mis en tablature de luth undated, [4] pages of manuscript music on 2 sheets; 34 cm.; Manuscript transcriptions in pencil and ink, including markings in red ink. The original published 1612 in Paris by Pierre Ballard. (Box 3, Folder 78)
    Sheet 1. Transcription of melodic line and accompanying texts. Airs Espagnole. 1. A ver mil damas hermosas (p. 61) -- 2. El baxel esta en la playa (p. 63) -- 3. Vuestros ojos tienen d'Amor (p. 63) -- Sheet 2. Transcription of melodic line, text, and accompanying lute tablature. Ballet de la Royne: [C]Es Ninses pleines de mespris (second livre p. 6, 1809) -- Pour la chaisne du mesme ballet: [N]os esprits libres (p. 7) -- La Renommee au Roy: [P]Leine de langues (p. 8).
  - Bergkreyen undated, 1 page of manuscript music; 34 cm.; Manuscript transcription in ink with melody line and text. (Box 3, Folder 79)
    Bergkreyen 1536. Jungfraulein, soll ich mit euch gehn in euren Rosengarden -- 68 Lieder 1542. Es ist ein Schnee gefallen -- Forster II: 1540. Der Gutzgauch auf dem zaune sass -- Forster II.: 1540. Ach Jungfrau, wollt ihr mit mir gahn -- Forster III: 1549. Mir ist ein schönesbraun meydelein
  - Bermudo, Juan Declaracio´n de instrumentos musicales. Selections Declaracio´n de instrumentos musicales, 1555, undated, 24 pages of manuscript music; 35 cm.; Manuscript in ink. Transcriptions from the part format of the original into keyboard format on double staves and full score. Title on wrapper: Beilage I Bermudo. Partially contained on pages 227-235 of Kinkeldey's Orgel und Klavier in der Musik des 16. Jahrhunderts. (Box 3, Folder 80)
    Fol. 61v -- Fol 78: Primero modo por [natural sign] mi (Der erste Modus auf) -- Fol. 77: Primero por Elami -- Fol. 78v: Octavo por Elami (Der achte Modus auf E.) -- Fol. 114v: Modo primero con resabios de quarto (Der erste Modus) -- Fol. 115: Modo quarto (Der vierte Modus) -- Fol. 116: Modo sexto verdadero (Der wahre sechste Modus) -- Fol. 117v: Modo octavo -- Fol. 118v: Conditur alme siderum -- Fol. 119: Vexilla regis prodeunt -- Fol. 119v: Veni creator spiritus -- Pange lingua.
  - Bermudo, Juan Declaracio´n de instrumentos musicales. Selections Declaracio´n de instrumentos musicales, Ossuna, 1555, undated, 24 pages of manuscript music; 34 cm.; Manuscript in ink. Transcriptions from the part format of the original into keyboard format on double staves and full score. Includes lute tablature. Partially contained on pages 227-235 of Kinkeldey's Orgel und Klavier in der Musik des 16. Jahrhunderts. (Box 3, Folder 81)
    Fol. Lxxxiii (Cap. xlii). Preceded by text "El que quisiere estra facilitado ..." -- Fol. cxiii(v): Text of "Para el lector" -- Fol. Cxiii: Ave maris stella -- Fol. Cxiiii: Cantus del modo primero con resabios de quarto -- Fol. Fol. Cxv(v): Cantus del modo quarto -- Fol. Cxvi(v): Cantus del modo sexto verdadero -- Fol. Cxvii(v): Cantus del modo octavo Fol. Cxviii(v): Cantus de conditor alme siderum -- Fol. Cxix: Vexilla regis prodeunt -- Fol. Cxix(v): Veni creator spiritus -- Pange lingua -- Fol. lxi(v): Illustration of scale passages -- Fol. lxxviii: Primero modo por [natural sign] mi (The accidental modes, after Chapter 35) -- Fol. lxxvii(v): Cantus del primero por Elami -- Fol. lxxviii(v): Cantus del octavo por Elami.
  - Borjon de Scellery, Pierre, 1633-1691 Traite de la musette. Selections Traite de la musette (Borjon) 1672. Bibl. Dresden. Musica A 46, undated, 2 pages of manuscript music; 34 cm.; Ink manuscript. Verso contains content from two books of tablature. (Box 3, Folder 82)
    Traite de la musette (Borjon). Seconde parte, fol. 7, Les tons du chalumeau simple; Prelude; Branle de Bresse avec le double; Branle de Lugny -- Tabulatur Buch auff dem Instrument (Bibl. Dresden Mscr. J 307m). Danket dem Herrn / Christianus Herzogk zu Sachssen -- Tabulatur Buch auff der Cythar. Danket dem Herrn / Johannes Georgius Hertzog zu Sachssen.
  - Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 Symphonies, no. 3, op. 90, F major. Allegro; arr. Dritte Symphonie, F dur, op. 90, Letzte Satz undated, 2 pages of manuscript music; 35 cm.; Manuscript (Pencil) First seventeen measures arranged for piano four hands. (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Brolo, Bartolomeo, fl. 1400-1440 Entrepis Berliner Liederbuch (Ms. Mus Z98) undated, 1 page of manuscript music; 34 cm.; Manuscript transcription of the first twenty measures in ink. Berliner Liederbuch is the former name for what is currently known as the Glogauer Liederbuch. (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Brunetti, Domenico, ca. 1580-1646 Euterpe. Sospir che del bel petto L'Euterpe di Domenico Brunetti, Bolognese. Opera musicali di madrigali, canzonette, arie, stanze, e scherzi diversi in dialoghi, & echo, a una, due, tre, et quattro voci, da cantarsi in theorba, arpicordo, & altri stromenti, ..., 1606 undated, 2 pages of manuscript music; 33 cm.; Ink manuscript. Melodic line, with words, and bass only. (Box 3, Folder 85)
    Sospir che del bel petto.
  - Buus, Giacques, d. 1565 Intabolatura d'organo Intabolatura d'organo di ricercari di M. Giacques Buus ... Libro primo, September 24, 1904, 34 pages of manuscript music; 35 cm.; Ink manuscript. Copied from the British Library K.1.f16, 1549 printing by Antonio Gardane. "London, Sept. 24, 1904"--At end of score. (Box 3, Folder 86)
    Recercar primo (Fol. Aii) -- Recercar secondo (Fol. D) -- Recercar terzo (Fol. F(v)) -- [Recercar quarto] (Fol. GII(v)).
  - Buus, Giacques, d. 1565 Intabolatura d'organo. No. 1 Ricercar no. 1 aus Intabolatura d'organo do ricercari di M. Giaches Buus, Lib. 1, Venetia 1549, undated, 20 pages of manuscript music; 33 cm.; Ink manuscript. This work is the first ricercar in Intabolatura d'organo and the first ricercar in the Ricercars, book 2 (1549). The transcription includes the first 38 measures of the full score on four staves from the latter source and the entire work from the Intabolatura on two staves. There is also a note indicating that a source for the full score version was Raymund Schlecht's Geschichte der Kirchenmusik (1879). Title on wrapper: Beilage III Buus. Contained on pages 245-259 of Kinkeldey's Orgel und Klavier in der Musik des 16. Jahrhunderts. (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Buus, Giacques, d. 1565 Ricercars, book 1. No. 1 Recercari di M. Iacques Buus ... Libro primo, undated, 6 pages of manuscript music; 36 cm.; Ink manuscript. Transcription on four staves of the first 79 measures. Information about Adriano Willaert's Fantasie Ricercari contrapunti a 3 voci (1559) is on the back cover. (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Buxheimer Orgelbuch Aus Buxheimer Orgelbuch. München Stadtbibliothek Ms. Mus 3725., undated, 3 pages of manuscript music; 36 cm.; Ink manuscript. Additional note in caption: Lute auch Attaignant Tabulature 26 chanson, 1530. Also identified as Bayerische Staatsbibliothek. Manuscript. Cim. 352b. (Box 3, Folder 89)
    No. 61: Pysque mammor -- No. 194: Praeambulum super C (fol. 109 ®)) -- No. 112: Praeambulum super d (fol. 61 (v)) -- [No. 236]: Sequitur fundamentum magistri Conradi paumann contrapuncti (Fol. 142 (v)).
  - Campion, Thomas, 1567-1620 Come let us sound with melodie the praises Come, let us sound with melody: songs from Rosseter's Book of Airs, 1601, undated, 1 page of manuscript music; 32 cm.; Ink manuscript. Transcription for keyboard and voice, with text beneath vocal line. (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Campion, Thomas, 1567-1620 Songs, lute, viol acc. Selections Booke of ayres, set foorth to be song to the lute, orpherian, and base violl ... 1601, undated, 13 pages of manuscript music; 33 cm.; Ink manuscript. The original collection contains 21 songs by Campion and 21 songs by Philip Rosseter. Transcription for keyboard and voice, with text beneath vocal line. (Box 3, Folder 91)
    My sweetest Lesbia; Though you are yoong and I am olde; I care not for these ladies; Follow thy faire sunne / Thomas Campion -- If she forsakes me; Sweete come againe; And would you see my Mistris face; No grave for woe; If I urge my kinde desires; What harts content can he finde; / Philip Rosseter.
  - Cavazzoni, Marco Antonio, ca. 1490-ca. 1560 Recerchari, motetti, canzoni. Selections Ricercari, motetti, canzoni composti per Marco Antonio da Bologna. Venetiis: Apud Bernardinum Vercelensem, 1523, undated, 30 pages of manuscript music; 26-31 cm.; Ink manuscript. "Transcripts from copy in British Museum by Otto Kinkeldey"--Title page. (Box 3, Folder 92)
    Recercar primo -- Salve virgo -- Recercar secondo -- O stella maris -- Perdone, Moi sie folie -- Madame vous, aves, mon, cuor -- Plus, ne regres (incomplete).
  - Cornelius, Peter, 1824-1874 Lieder, op. 5. Zum Ossa sprach der Pelion Zum Ossa sprach der Pelion, op. 5, no. 5, undated, 3 pages of manuscript music; 26 x 32 cm.; Ink manuscript. Text by Annette von Droste-Hülshoff. (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Flecha, Matheo, ca. 1530-1604 Harmonia a 5 Harmonia a 5, composto e dedicata alla Maesta dell'Imperatore Massimiliano II l'anno 1568 dal Fra. Matheo Fleccia Carmelita, Capelano della Imperatrice Maria*, undated, 4 pages of manuscript music; 26 x 32 cm.; Ink manuscript. Transcription of Flecha's only known instrumental work from the Bibliothek der Gesellschaft der Musikfreunde, Wien Reg. 23573. Page 4 contains the beginning of a lute tablature, "Les doubles follies d'Espagne" from Ms. 17706 in the Ö¨sterreichische Nationalbibliothek and first eight measures of a keyboard transcription of "Prélude en de la ré sol. Suitte. Folies d'espagne" from Ms. 19455 in the Ö¨sterreichische Nationalbibliothek. (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Folies d'Espagne, undated, 8 pages of manuscript music; 26 x 33 cm.; Ink manuscript. "See Niecks in Musical Times, 1888"--Caption. Refers to, and includes examples from the article, Folies d'Espagne: A Study by Fr. Niecks ( Niecks, Frederick, 1845-1924)in Musical Times, Dec. 1, 1888 (vol. 29, no. 550: 717-721). Muiscal transcriptions accompanied by textual notes. (Box 3, Folder 95)
    Toccate e partite d'intavolatura di cimbalo (1615). Partite sopra Folia / [Girolamo] Frescobaldi -- Arie per il Balletto à Cavallo (1667). Follia per nuovo ingresso ... / Johann Heinrich Schmelzer -- Farinell's Ground / [Jean-Baptiste Farinel, or Giovanni Battista Farinelli] -- [Suonata a violino e violone o cembalo]. No. 12 / [Arcangelo] Corelli -- Pieces de clavecin (1689). Variations sur les folies d'Espagne / Jean Henri d'Anglebert -- Bauern-Cantate (1742). [Unser lieber Kammerherr] / J. S. Bach -- Sonate da camera a tre, op. 1. Follia XII / Antonio Vivaldi.
  - Franck, Melchior, d. 1639 Fasciculus quodlibeticus. Ein Mägdlein stund Fasciculus quodlibeticus: Ein Mägdlein stund, undated, 12 manuscript music parts (2 pages each); 18 x 27 cm.; Three parts each for Soprano, Alto, Tenor, and Bass. First line of text: Wo stund sie denn. Originally issued Coburg, 1611. (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Fugger, Octavianus, II, 1549-1600 Passameggio del gropo e sua galiarda Hof. Wien Ms. 18821. Lautenbuch. O.S.F. 1562. Passameggio del gropo, undated, 4 pages of manuscript music; 35 cm.; Ink manuscript. The three works from Ms. 18821 are transcribed as lute tablature with transcription for keyboard. The Recercar (anonymous composer) from Ms. 18827 is only in lute tablature. (Box 3, Folder 97)
    Lautenbach des Octavian Secundus, 1562. (Mus. Hs. 18821). Passameggio del gropo y sua galiarda; Del gropo minuita (fol. 5 b.); Opus non inscriptum (fol. 6b.) -- [Lautenbuch]. [italienische Lautentabulatur]. XVI. Jh. 39 Bl. Mus. Hs. 18827. Recercar.
  - Gabrieli, Giovanni, ca. 1554-1612 Canzoni et sonate. Canzon, voices (7) (No. 7) Canzone VII aus Canzoni et Sonate, 1615, undated, 4 pages of manuscript music; 35 cm.; Ink manuscript. Incomplete. (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Gabrieli, Giovanni, ca. 1554-1612 Canzoni et sonate. Canzon, voices (12) (No. 17) Canzoni XVII aus Canzoni et Sonate, 1615, undated, 15 pages of manuscript music; 35 cm.; Manuscript (Pencil, copied over with ink). "Ed. P. F. Thaddeo da Venetia Agostiniano"--Caption. (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Gabrieli, Giovanni, ca. 1554-1612 Sacrae symphoniae. Sonata pian e forte Sonata piano e forte alla quarta bassa, Venedig 1597, Bearbeitung von Otto Kinkeldey, undated, 1 manuscript score (11 pages); 24 x 33 cm. and 8 manuscript parts; 35 cm.; Ink manuscript. (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Gabrieli, Giovanni, ca. 1554-1612 Sacrae symphoniae. Sonata pian e forte Sonata piano e forte, undated, 3 pages of manuscript music; 35 cm.; Ink manuscript. Incomplete; first 38 measures only. (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Gabrieli, Giovanni, ca. 1554-1612 Sacrae symphoniae. Surrexit Christus Motetto 16 aus Symph. Sacrae, 1615. Surrexit Christus ..., undated, 1 leaf of manuscript music; 34 cm.; Ink manuscript. Measures 59-64 of Motet 14 from the second book of Symphoniae Sacrae, starting with the text, Annunciate populus. (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Galilei, Vincenzo, d. 1591 Fronimo. Selections Fronimo. Dialogo di Vincenzo Galilei. Venezia 1584 (Erste Ausgabe 1596), undated, 3 pages of manuscript music; 33 cm.; Ink manuscript. Contained on pages 283-285 of Kinkeldey's Orgel und Klavier in der Musik des 16. Jahrhunderts. Transcription in keyboard format. Pages numbered 25-27. Accompanied by leaf marked Beilage V. (Box 3, Folder 103)
    Ricercare del primo tuono per [natural sign] p. 80 -- Ricercare del sesto tuono per [natural sign] p. 81 -- Ricercare del settimo tuono per [natural sign] p. 82.
  - Galli, Giuseppe, fl. 1598 Totius primi libri sacri operis musici. Mantegazza La mantegazza: Totius libri primi sacri operis musici alterius modulis concinendi partitio seu quam praestantiss. Auctore Josepho Gallo. Studio et labore Aurelii Ribrochi edita. Mediolani 1598., undated, 6 pages of manuscript music; 24 x 33 cm.; Ink manuscript. Transcribed in keyboard format. Pages numbered 9-14. (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Gerle, Hans, ca. 1500-1570 Musica teutsch. Selections Abschriften aus Hans Gerle Musica teutsch, Nuremberg, 1532, undated, 19 pages of manuscript music; 34 cm.; Ink manuscript. "Nach S. W. Dehn's [ Dehn, S. W. (Siegfried Wilhelm), 1799-1858] Uebertragung, Berlin, 1861 [i.e. 1851]"--Title page. This is Ms. 7370 in the Staatsbibliothek zu Berlin. Transcriptions of tablature and keyboard realizations. (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Hassler, Hans Leo, 1564-1612 Lustgarten neuer teutscher Gesäng. Mein G'müt ist mir verwirret Lustgarten. Eine Sammlung deutsche Lieder zu vier fünf sechs und achte Stimmen ... (1601). XXIV. Mein G'müt ist mir verwirret, undated, 1 leaf of manuscript music; 33 cm.; Ink manuscript. (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Henry VIII, King of England, 1491-1547 Pastyme with good companye Pastyme with good companye, undated, 1 leaf of manuscript music; 34 cm.; Ink manuscript. Title from first line of text. "See Archaeologia 41 (1867)"--Caption. It is a reference to William Chappell's article, with transcriptions, Some account of an unpublished collection of songs and ballads by Henry VIII and his contemporaries. "From the Lamb Ms."--Caption. The manuscript is currently in the British Library as Add. 31922. (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Josquin, des Prez, d. 1521 Stabat Mater dolorosa/Comme femme desconforte´e Stabat mater dolorosa. Vocum Josquin de Pres. Aus Sebastian Ochsenkuhn's Tabulaturbuch auff die Lauten, Heidelberg, 1558, undated, 4 pages of manuscript music; 35 cm.; Ink manuscript. Incomplete; transcription of five-voice setting accompanied by Ochsenkuhn's version transcribed on two staves. Includes notes about other sources. (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - Judenku¨nig, Hans, ca. 1450-1526 Lute music. Selections Twelve selections in lute tablature from two works (1523) by Hans Judenkünig, undated, 12 pages of manuscript music; 26 x 33 cm.; Manuscript transcription in ink of lute tablature. (Box 4, Folder 109)
    Utilis et compendiaria introductio. Ode prima Mecoenas atavis -- Madonna katerina, oder hast du mich genummen -- Christ ist erstanden -- Hast du mich genumen.
    Schone kunstliche Underweisung. Pavana alla Veneciana -- Das erst Priamell -- Ayn niderlendisch runden dantz -- Das ander Priamell -- Das drit Priamel -- Das fierd Priamel -- Ain Spaniyelischer hoff dantz -- Tropolus secret.
  - Kern, Jerome, 1885-1945 How'd you like to spoon with me, undated, 1 leaf of manuscript music; 16 x 25 cm.; Ink manuscript marked "Violin". (Box 4, Folder 110)
    On verso: Pencil manuscript piano reduction of opening measures of Richard Wagner's opera, Tristan und Isolde.
  - Kleber, Leonhard, ca. 1495-1556 Tabulatur fu¨r die Orgel. Selections Tabulatur fu¨r die Orgel: scriptum et finitum per Leonardum Kleber de Geppingen ultimaDecembrius 1524: Phorze in aedibus meio, undated, 24 pages of manuscript music; 35 cm.; Ink manuscript transcriptions. From the manuscript 40026 in the Staatsbibliothek Preussischer Kulturbesitz Berlin, Musikabteilung. (Box 4, Folder 111)
    Abrecht die zyt -- Preambulum in re -- Philephos aves in fa, quatuor vocum, manualiter -- Preambulum in sol [natural] durum -- Preambulum in sol [flat] molle -- In fide recta -- Carmen italicum: Lemit le jor -- Si sumpsero: in ut manualiter -- Menter tota: in sol -- Illetadum bonum -- Lalahe: in ut manualiter -- Fantasy in fa -- La Spania in re / [Hans Buchner] -- Preambulum in ut manualiter -- Fors seulement in la [natural].
  - Kotter, Hans, ca. 1485-1541 Kotter Tabulatur: Basel (Bibl. Publ. Basiliensis) F IX 22: Sum Bonifacii Amerbachii Basiliensis: Nec muto dominum MDXIII, undated, 33 pages of manuscript music; 35 cm.; Ink manuscript transcriptions. Selections from tablature compiled by Hans Kotter in 1518, held in Universita¨tsbibliothek Basel. Two manuscript leaves inserted with additional source material for Tanzmass Benzenauer. (Box 4, Folder 112)
    Fundamentum totius artis musice artificialiter compositum et primo notandum cognoscere claves clavicordii -- Harmonia in sol / Kotter -- Fortuna d'un gran tempo / Josquin -- Fantasia in ut / Kotter -- Spanieler / Kotter -- Prooemium in re / Kotter -- Preludium in la / Kotter -- Avaßo?? in fa / Kotter -- Praeambulum in fa / [Kotter] -- Prooemium in re / Kotter -- Preludium in fa / Kotter -- Praeambulum in sol / Kotter -- Dantz moss. Benczenavher [Tanzmass Benzenauer and Nachtanz] / M.H.V. Constatz [Hans Buchner] -- Expecta ung pauco / Anonymous -- Ach hülf mich leid und semlich klag: 1.b / zu Constantz [Hans Buchner] --
  - Lasso, Orlando di, 1532-1594 Chansons, voices (4-6), book 3. Susanne ung jour Susanne ung jour. 1. 5 Stimmung Satz von Lassus, 2. Orgelbearbeitung von Andrea Gabrieli, 3. Anfang der Orgelbearbeitung von Ammerbach, undated, 12 pages of manuscript music; 33 cm.; Ink manuscript. Two scores vertically aligned. The top score is in five staves for the five-voice setting of Lasso's work. The bottom score is the keyboard arrangement of Lasso's work on two staves. It is from the publication, Canzoni alla francese et ricercari ariosi tabulate per sonar sopra istromenti da tasti dall Andrea Gabrieli. Libro V. Venetia, 1605. There is a separate five-stave transcription ([3] pages) of the first fourteen measures of the Ammerbach tablature (1571). The first fourteen measure numbers of the Gabrieli score are marked with red pencil to indicate where the Ammerbach would align. Contained on pages 264-274 of Kinkeldey's Orgel und Klavier in der Musik des 16. Jahrhunderts. (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - Lasso, Orlando di, 1532-1594 Princeps Marte potens, Guilelmus. Selections Princeps Marte potens, undated, 5 pages of manuscript music; 27 x 34 cm. and 42 parts; 16-34 cm.; Ink manuscript. Parts for soprano 1, 2, Alto 1,2, Tenor 1,2, and Bass 1, 2. (Box 4, Folder 114)
    1st part: Princeps Marte potens -- 9th part: Vive pater patriae.
  - Legrenzi, Giovanni, 1626-1690 Sonatas, op. 8. Fugazza. Selections Sonata von Gio. Legrenzi aus Sonate a 3-5 & sei stromenti (1663). La Fugazza, undated, 1 leaf of manuscript music; 34 cm.; Ink manuscript music of first twelve measures. For Viol I and II, Viol alto, Viol tenore, and Viol da brazzo. (Box 4, Folder 115)
  - Lemlin, Lorenz, b. ca. 1495 Gutzgauch auf dem Zaune sass Der Gutzgauch, undated, 12 manuscript parts; 12 x 27 cm.; For Soprano I and II, Alto, Tenor, and Bass I and II. (Box 4, Folder 116)
  - Lorenzo, da Firenze, d. 1372 or 3 A poste messe A poste messe, Florenz Med Laur. Am 87, Magister Laurentius da Florentia, undated, 4 pages of manuscript music; 34 cm.; Ink manuscript. Transcription from Biblioteca Medicea-Laurenziana, Med. Palatino 87, Squarcialupi Codex, fol. 49v. Transcription of the top voice only and no text. (Box 4, Folder 117)
  - Lorenzo, da Firenze, d. 1372 or 3 Ita se n'er'a star Magister Laurentius de Florentia: Flor. Med. Laur. Pal 87: Wolf III No. 49 p. 119, undated, 5 pages of manuscript music; 34 cm.; Ink manuscript. Transcription from Biblioteca Medicea-Laurenziana, Med. Palatino 87, Squarcialupi Codex, fol. 46v. First phrase of text: Ita se n'er'a star. (Box 4, Folder 118)